Guide to the Yale Law Library Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Law Library records
1937-2006
RU 786
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.75
(4 boxes)
The records consist of memoranda, surveys, reports, policies, lectures, donor correspondence and journals documenting the holdings and operations of the Yale Law Library.
Yale Law Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 26-E (YRG 26-E), Records of departments, offices, programs, and project of the Yale Law School.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of memoranda, surveys, reports, policies, lectures, donor correspondence and journals documenting the holdings and operations of the Yale Law Library.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the University of Illinois, 2011.
Law libraries; Yale Law Library; Yale Law School; Yale University -- Libraries
- Records, 1937-1991; Accession 1991-A-119
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2026
  - Law Library Exhibits, 1963-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibits, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Foreign and International Law Library, 1972-1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Interlibrary Loans, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Law Library Directors, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Law Library Funds: Acq. Dept., 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Law Library Memorandums, 1971-1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Law Library Network Conference, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Law Library Renovation Awards, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Law Library Schedules, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Law Library Room Space Survey, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Law Library Staff Photographs, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Law Library Staff, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Law Library Statistics, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Annual Reports
    - 1974 - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1980 - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1985 -1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Librarians, Yale Law School, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Librarian's Annual Report [not in box]
  - Library Resources Council, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Library Resource Council, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - ABA AALS: Annual Survey Reports, 1977-1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Affirmative Action (HEW), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Agency for International Development, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Black Law Students Association, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Racial Matters Committee, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Charpentier Memorial, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Commencement, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Dean's Reports, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Dean Search, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Education Planning and Curriculum, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Energy Conservation Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Faculty Committees, 1978-1990 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - First Term Teaching Assistants, 1977-1989 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - First Term Small Groups, 1972-1990 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Handicapped Students, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - I.L.S.
    - Financial, 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Councils, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - 1965 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - 1969 - 1971 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - 1966 - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Yale Law School
    - Fall Term Examinations, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Mid-Year Examinations, February, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Mid-Year Examinations, February, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Manuscripts - Jerome Frank (Transferred to Jerome Frank Papers MS# 222)
  - Rutledge Papers, The Wiley B. (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - I.L.S. -- Annual Reports, 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Insurance, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Knapp - (Law School windows), 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Law and Modernization, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Internal Revenue, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Copyright Contracts, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Law and Social Action, 1971-1983 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Law School Administrative Committee on Security, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Shelving, 1967-1976 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Storrs Lectures, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Student Representatives, 1970-1978 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Telephone System - Law School, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - University Council - Law School Committee, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Women Law Students, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Women of Color and the Law Collective, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Yale Advocate, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Yale Association of International Law, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Law Journal, 1961-1985 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Yale Law Journal Bylaws, 1975-1983 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Yale Law Observer, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Yale Law School Association, 1970-1986 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Arthur Charpentier Files
    - Science and Technology (J. Goldstein) (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Yale Law School Financial Information (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Yale Law Journal (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - American Institute of Architects' Award of Excellence, 1980
  - American Institute of Architects' Honor Award
  - Notes and Drafts for Frederick Hicks' History of Law and Other Books
    - Prudential Committee Excerpts Regarding the Law Schools (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Juris Prudence: Notes on Opinions of Some Modern Writers (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Law School Chronology (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Copies of Financial Papers, Correspondence, etc. (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Typed Draft: William Howard Taft Yale Professor of Law and New Haven Citizen. Frederic C. Hicks, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Notes on Taft, W. H. from the Journal Courrier (Box 3, Folder 77)
- Law Library records, 1981-2006; Accession 2013-A-013
  Scope and Contents
  The records consist of donor correspondence; documents pertaining to performance and promotion policies and procedures for law library employees; and documents pertaining to transfers of materials from the law library to other libraries and archival repositories.
  The records are restricted until January 1, 2042.
  - Yale Law Library manuscripts - transfer files, 1981-2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)